<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heraa Ali</title>
    <link>http://www.heraaali.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Heraa Ali</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.heraaali.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Data Analysis</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/spotify/</guid>
      <description>After Spotify did their end-of-the-year summary of my listening history, I was inspired to do more analysis on my listening data. Instead of just including the output of my work, I am going to go through my code to provide an easy-to-follow resource if you&#39;re a programmer who is new to Python, although I am assuming familiarity with coding in general.
If you request it, Spotify will let you download a year&#39;s worth of listening history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook Tips</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>I use Jupyter Notebook both at my day job and for my own projects - if you&#39;ve used it, you know it&#39;s a great tool for data cleaning, visualization, and quick scratch work. And I discovered shortcuts for it entirely by accident: I hit D twice and, to my horror, deleted a cell. Can’t win them all, but you can learn a host of useful shortcuts!
Note Jupyter Notebook has two different keyboard input modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Website</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/hugo/</guid>
      <description>To make this website, I used the Hugo static site generator and am hosting my site on GitHub pages. What does that mean?
GitHub Pages allows you to host a static site, either on the github.io domain or a custom domain, and is free if you have a GitHub account. I created a GitHub user/organization page, which means that my site is available at &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io. The steps are outlined in the documentation for GitHub pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Heraa.
I am a software engineer at Intel. Before that, I studied applied mathematics at the University of California, Berkeley. I made this website to talk about side projects &amp;amp; to share tutorials from what I&#39;ve learned along the way. More than anything, I am interested in exploring the space where math, coding, and communication meet up and hang out.
When I’m not building products, you can find me doing yoga, reading, or traveling somewhere new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/git/</guid>
      <description>Mastering source control is essential for a software developer, but Git can get a little confusing when you’re first starting out. Here is a list of commands to use as a reference &amp;ndash; I&#39;ve included all the basics you would need to use Git from the command line.
   Command Description     git status Check the status of the current branch.   git branch List the current branches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>