<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heraa Ali</title>
    <link>http://www.heraaali.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Heraa Ali</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.heraaali.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheat Sheet Volume II</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/more_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/more_git/</guid>
      <description>Just can&#39;t Git enough? Below are a list of useful Git commands to reference once you&#39;ve memorized the basics.
Setup:    Command Description     git config -global user.name &amp;ldquo;First Last&amp;rdquo; Set a name   git config &amp;ndash;global color.ui auto automatic command line coloring for Git   git init Initialize an existing directory as a Git repo   git clone [url] Make a working copy of an entire repository    Rewriting history:    Command Description     git log Show all commits in current branch&#39;s history   git rebase feature-branch Apply commits of a current branch ahead of a specific one    Update from remote repo:    Command Description     git merge other-branch Merge a different branch into your active branch   git diff Preview changes before merging    Undo local changes:    Command Description     git checkout &amp;ndash; example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Data Analysis</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/spotify/</guid>
      <description>After Spotify did their end-of-the-year summary of my listening history, I was inspired to do more analysis on my listening data. Instead of just including the output of my work, I am going to go through my code to provide an easy-to-follow resource if you&#39;re a programmer who is new to Python, although I am assuming familiarity with coding in general.
If you request it, Spotify will let you download a year&#39;s worth of listening history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook Tips</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>I use Jupyter Notebook both at my day job and for my own projects - if you&#39;ve used it, you know it&#39;s a great tool for data cleaning, visualization, and quick scratch work. And I discovered shortcuts for it entirely by accident: I hit D twice and, to my horror, deleted a cell. Can’t win them all, but you can learn a host of useful shortcuts!
Note Jupyter Notebook has two different keyboard input modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Website</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/hugo/</guid>
      <description>To make this website, I used the Hugo static site generator and am hosting my site on GitHub pages. What does that mean?
GitHub Pages allows you to host a static site, either on the github.io domain or a custom domain, and is free if you have a GitHub account. I created a GitHub user/organization page, which means that my site is available at &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io. The steps are outlined in the documentation for GitHub pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Heraa.
I am a software engineer at Intel. Before that, I studied applied mathematics at the University of California, Berkeley. I am interested in the space where math, coding, and communication meet up and hang out. When I am not writing code, you can find me doing yoga, reading, or traveling somewhere new.
And I&#39;m happy just because.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heraaali.com/blog/git/</guid>
      <description>Mastering source control is essential for a software developer, but Git can get a little confusing when you’re first starting out. Here is a list of commands to use as a reference &amp;ndash; I&#39;ve included all the basics you would need to use Git from the command line.
   Command Description     git clone Check out a repository   git add example.txt Add the changed file to staging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>